knowledge is power
[Music]
yeah yeah no i i entirely understand
that uh i i tend to do the same thing
listening back as i've been doing these
podcast episodes i listen back to myself
and i'm like i know what i was talking
about but i don't think that the people
listening to so
um that's that's just fine with me so
welcome everyone welcome set i
appreciate your time once again um can
we just start with uh i would like to
start with uh if you're willing your
personal background kind of how you even
got into these subjects like what what
led you in this direction
um
the general the direction was human
rights
and that as it has
i read and i studied
at university about human rights
uh and maybe also um
[Music]
uh
subject that have been
sensitive to
personal experience of from having
heard
stories or seen people a victim
victim of
of
horrific situation in poor quarters for
example
i mean
in the case of human trafficking
it's not
it's not like a poor
country's situation near live in
europe
in rich countries and
and there is human trafficking happening
where whereas
well obviously where people are more
exploitable
um
for example um
the criteria are
of being exploited
or being trafficked and
this even in europe
uh
also
what is um
that uh
on amplify the taboo about trafficking
is that trafficking is a new world
it has been officialized only into the
year 2000
by the u.n and by the u.s this before i
was not considered a crime so for in the
example of um
of sexual exploitation he was treated as
prostitution
so basically um
of course the the the term before uh
used to be slavery
but uh
so
uh yes there are
like um
concepts such as rape or you know maybe
coercion and so forth but he was really
more confused in the law and certainly
less
tackled because you the the gerardic
system was weak is still very weak but
was even weaker uh before sorry
trafficking is um
is a word by up and very very recently
but uh
it's it you don't have to go very far to
uh um
to to to see uh people that are
uh trafficked uh sexually in
what was called a prostitution of
um
of
for example um
a migrant illegal migrate migrant this
person
will be
criminalized
um
because of having no paper for example
it doesn't matter
and it's still the case and if this one
is still the case with
with uh
children so people under 18
but
at least in the us it's still the case
it's
notoriously lovely case but
people who are complete victim of
trafficking are effect criminalized
because because yes or because they have
been targeted
because they are illegal immigrants
so
no one will will
[Music]
say oh yeah but you are trafficked
because any other trafficker gets away
with the vat because they are called
smugglers in instead i'm not saying
there is no smugglers smugglers exist
but the traffickers which are not
smugglers or
are part of smuggling because
one of the
bigger
uh
way of
of luring people into trafficking is to
say
well you know there's
a in another country there's a good job
waiting for you and uh and uh oh simply
because they've they've got to
migrate because of economic or
safety security issue and so forth yeah
yeah yeah yeah it's one of them
uh parameters
in the definition of human trafficking
is coercion
coercion or um
or people that uh
yeah that make make you think that uh
you you are not trafficked but you are
basically so is
is what is the simplest and what is done
is that
they they make people believe they will
get a job
and instead of a job
they are made slaves
yeah and there's no there's no way for
them to
to react in in case of migrants it's um
it's uh
uh i think it's like kind of easy for
the mafia because you know we can't
uh before before knowing that you you
you
you don't think it's possible because
these people
[Music]
if they are forced and they are in
prison
but in fact they are in the streets so
you would think that they can go and
sell the police and so forth and you
know stop the circle happening but this
is not their situation their situation
is that they are for example illegal uh
they have got nowhere to go they've got
they are in
economic
found they are extremely poor
probably
trafficking is so such a
is such an excess of torture that uh
um
drugs there's drug-related
addiction uh
and so forth and for for the illegal
migrants anya
and maybe also inside it's very easy for
the mafia because they tell them you
know what if you are if you go we know
where you live we know we know where
your family is and there will be a
retribution
so they can't even go back because
and you have yeah so
so so okay so you're coming to me from
france right
yeah yeah yeah yeah and i'm over over
here in texas in america so what in
where you're at and where i'm at um what
does what does trafficking look like so
um is this
i mean because i feel that that my level
of knowledge on human trafficking is
kind of just from movies and occasional
news articles that i see like i don't
really know exactly how how it happens
so um and where you're at and where i'm
at how are people lured in and and how
can we um how can we spread awareness to
to help each other out and look out for
for signs and symptoms um or um to just
have more knowledge to
to help each other out you know before
preventative wise so um
i just feel knowledge is power there so
this would take
you we need a professional to turn
service here but
a few words like i can say on this is
that
for example in in the case of of
children
what
organization will tell you on and on and
on is that there is a trap
a big trap is that um
there is not st stereotype
person
but there is a trafficker for example
okay
yeah so
it's not it's not as easy as that to
recognize
for example for children as well
there is a there is examples and in fact
they are more
they are really more common than one
would think but is not you know a child
that would be
a completely um
imprisoned uh
into sexual slavery
what uh
might be the
almost the common
place situation is by a child by still
socialized
so even if you see us as a
child at school
it doesn't mean that during the weekend
it
it is not
trafficked basically
in the u.s in france
in europe maybe in the uk it's uh it's
worse but in france i think uh
you know we there's more social
protection and so forth so it's it's
less threatening at the moment but in
the us and this is state figures and
it's not organization figures it's
really official figure from
from the u.s state department yeah there
is a three hundred thousand
uh child um
at risk of sexual uh um entry at risk of
sexual exploitation a year
three hundred thousand uh children
in the u.s
and
yeah
so of course it is completely insane it
is that
but
maybe this figure might might be
explained because um
kind of
not lessened but explained because the
volume is so incredible yeah but
you might be at at risk of exploitation
once
not in a at a regular basis here
also it's explained by the social
situation
big atrocities like this
doesn't
happen in
any so
the volume of it because of course
um uh
isolated example uh there's
this kind of uh
um
[Music]
they are very comp
complicated to prevent yeah but so uh so
a
large amount of people victim of it are
explained by a social situation
homelessness
explain a lot
i mean
the children
that will
be trafficked
classically they will be from
the social services
the social services are
the longest history of not being
responsible for the children they are
under their care
it is not obvious that
if you are a a child
in
like in care of us
cared by the social
in foster family or you know omen so
forth the the the amount of
of proportion of
these kids
ending up in criminality
and
prostitution is is
really high
and
this might be explained by
by of course by
something that is very difficult to uh
to replace uh a good quality parenting
also because
there is this problem but
you are dealing sometimes with children
that have got the
experience uh trauma sometimes extreme
traumas and are eating their out of the
door my 18 years certainly still a baby
and there is no work for you and so
forth and is the opened
open door are being predated and
basically
and
and it's what is done
obviously
uh and um
um
[Music]
yeah
yeah it that is um yeah it's so terrible
i didn't realize that the numbers were
that high i mean
you know you see yeah
i insist on this figure because uh i
you know
um
the figures about the human slavery as
it's so impressive but from time the
figures and the the facts
is so there's it's sort of so
overwhelming and completely uh
but you didn't know you were part of
this culture but
you you you spend the times
checking the fact
and rechecking the fact because you
think at one point or no but i must have
misread it okay
it's been i find it 10 in 10 10 times
but
where is the official sources and you
know to do and i can make the more
academic job on it but every time i'm
i'm like
i've got to check that every time i
spend like hours checking what the
official source is it's it's very
official and
it is yeah
yeah wow wow wow so we're so
where are we at in the in the you know
fight against it in the resolution in
solving solving the problem so what do
we i mean obviously we have people like
you who are spreading awareness and your
blog is very helpful for these sorts of
things the work that you do um but what
who else what other types of people do
you work with what are the movements
that you guys
have going on um
you know first i don't know if my blog
is really useful because even as
as a way to uh
to
[Music]
distribute information we've got a bone
we've got a lot of problems with fake
news and so forth but it's kind of
amusing when you uh when you do
something with university for example
where where um
the the data and the checking from
whatever i i'm not sure people read
because um
um
every time we want to refer to uh
official sources right so basically what
is on the web is very wide scope but
what we are um trying to aim at is is
very restrictive because
yeah because i mean at university it's a
beta 11 but in university you can't even
say that um
you know you you saw uh
the secondary source is from a website
for example so that is regarded
reviewed yeah so if you are not uh
writing this from uh
from your office
at university this won't be
this won't be
read basically right so even though even
even the guys at university are not read
so
you know
there is a
there is a question about um
if if really information is circulating
and and what it's worth of course it is
worth but you see you you ask me about
what we are doing
me i can only speak to for myself
i try to
for very particular
[Music]
topic uh uh well i would have been
interested in in working for
organization but uh
i couldn't i mean
i couldn't get employed so this is
but
i i wanted to um
not as a as a volunteer not not not not
to get paid
to uh to reach people to reach
organization about one topic in
particular that i think was regarded
even by professional
especially professional uh uh against uh
try to fight slavery and sexual slavery
in particular and this was for example
the
uh the fact that uh
there is a religion
uh who regard their highest
clerics or in the case of islam for
example their profit
and so as as of course the ultimate
model as we all know because it's
it's one of
on the first formula that that is
circulating and there and that when you
realize that
the prophet of islam uh for example has
got four spars and the fourth one is
mainly uh
from most
people from
the islam
religion will tell you that she's
underage and well on their age but most
people believe in most scripture that
she's under 10
when the
when she's been
well
well sexually enslaved by uh by mohammed
basically and uh and also sexual slavery
in islam was
under uh this prophet was
he was in the book it was in it is
inscribed
in in what
uh one of uh what is
say to be holy books yes so sexual
slavery murders and
and bleeding and so forth
uh it is inscribed and so uh for example
i
i tried to contact organization on this
topic and
i couldn't
try to
target more specialized organization
and
every time the answer and then i
followed foo because it's not
you know i said i may have sent
thousands of email uh to for to to
people for
um
to people to um
to speak about uh
more than human slavery but to human
rights here but this uh i did follow you
fool yeah i i really rang and you know
and try to to obtain an answer and the
answer is no no no it's not our area we
can't do that it's not our area and via
the other guy there is no more
specialized
than this than when he's slavery that is
only
there is also um a bizarre fact about
bizarre
he's a
uh it's not fast
um
i don't have english last sorry so sad
basically
uh
it's it's only in 2017
that charlemage
he has been regarded as human
trafficking
only in 2017
before it was
basically
not
not regarded as slavery basically it was
like uh
um
[Music]
regarded as you know uh traditional
certainly like this traditional or
cultural uh aberration certainly but
it's only uh
by the u.n
by the united nations just incorporated
child marriage into their slavery
figures only in 2017
he's very big to know that because it
means that um
uh
five years ago
camarilla didn't have um
legal protection you know the cha the
one it's disgusting to to use this term
right because
it's not you know it's uh
it's not my age at all i mean it's it's
just that it's it's slavery on on a
piece of paper it's like um and just
just
and yeah so it's only since 2017 that
shall marriage benefit from
slavery closure on it before it was you
know just marriage and also this ma for
example with chair marriage is really um
underestimate and the reason why it's
underestimated is because for example
unesco
the right of child convention has been
signed by every countries in the world
the only country that didn't sign it in
the u.s
and somalia
why did the uf not sign it uh hello this
is uh
this is a bit of a
of a mock that is using
at university
because when you when you look at the
legal perspective on it
they will say the the
the people
that advocate for not signing it we'll
tell you no no no but you know what our
legal framework
are really better we're not gonna sign
for convention that is um
but is
less by our own standards
but is this is absolute uh
joke to say that because one
you you've
a convention is a convention so and yeah
uh
it's not a treaty so you don't have to
follow it you know also there's the law
the law is the spirit of the law you
follow the letter of the law but you
spread over spirit of the law and means
that if you sign a paper that are
promoting a child right
even if there's a problem with a letter
uh
evil if the spirit of the law say no no
you protect child what is certainly not
to abuse
children right you see so whatever but
this is a big joke the reason why uh the
u.s didn't sign it is because you still
practice participation
do you think i really like you said
spirit of the law i think that's very
important i think that's something that
we're losing a lot of is is the essence
the spirit of the law
rather than just following the
like how you're talking about you keep
getting transferred to different people
they're like oh that's not our
department or we don't handle that or
whatever
and we're following the script too much
you know where where
the the
yeah the spirit of the law is not being
followed we forget what it's all about
right
yeah
yeah but also
the problem will be uh as well that is a
constant um subject of argument
this this would be the problem is that
i mean
we are from different
system from
roman law and common law so uh
yes how to interpret laws and is very
big in the u.s or in the uk because he's
the judge is doing the job basically
instead of
of just um
uh applying the law this is more
european
in roman law the judge will be more
applying the laws you know and in the
u.s and the uk so anglophone um
[Music]
even so commonwealth and so forth uh the
judges are
really
much more important
because
because they will interpret the a lot of
more
but
the problem is that
also with that clear letter and you know
clear
framework
then it's
it's a bit they do whatever they want on
top they're extremely extremely uh
powerful because they are it's it's the
rule of precedent that is to say if they
do something once uh the judge the other
judges is gonna read about what they
they did and they will follow precedent
so it's why you why you have been
so big story with your supreme court and
the
because judges
yes so independent whatever yeah
so yes so
yeah we are caught in a new race
yeah it's it's so silly we're uh yeah
we're mistaking the the map for the
territory in many ways um you've talked
you've talked about censorship i think
censorship is a is an important topic
because
i mean it's it's filtering in with our
advancement of technology and the
internet and you know even things like
youtube um
we're really starting to
to say this is truth and this is not
truth and these companies are are
blocking certain content you know around
the uh the pandemic the corona 19 virus
all this stuff it's uh
it's getting more and more complicated
so i think that censorship is important
to talk about i know that you've spoken
on the censorship in china and i think
that is a good a good place to go i
think it's a good place to to to look at
um for for what we don't like
yeah yeah
censorship is everywhere
yeah
censorship is everywhere it's in every
country
when you study the capitalist
way of producing censorship and fight is
done
for self-censorship
there is very interesting paper on
on our uh
uh
basically uh
the audience is sensor is on
censoring the artist
uh the publisher is censoring the offer
and the author is censoring himself
because they they want to uh
they want to they cannot not
be
doing some some sales and so forth so
censorship it's it's really everywhere
but in china
it's uh
it's it's the top league basically yeah
and also china being a one-party system
this is
changing
the whole game
by the way today they just said that
at school the
the the pupils will will have to learn
about qi so the president
um
reform and political uh
spirit of philosophy and so forth right
so
is a sign from we know about chana but
is going on and on and on you know
china is as a as other history of or at
least i have been told i've been told
that
of closing
and opening and closing and opening and
closing and so
uh 15 years ago you were
it was a
opening uh
phase
and it's um
yes it's ten years ago uh
yes i think it's ten years ago maybe
maybe a little bit less where
well since you see
because
because for example he became a chief of
the army for example yeah so more and
more concentrated power
and um and uh
yeah censorship in china well it's so
full yeah you know for example um
and
i guess yeah yes for sure he has he has
already been the case uh
but china is still um like a
secret continent almost here
you know
it's completely another scripture and so
forth it's a bit secret it's it's uh
it's communist so he is also kept there
their secret uh well
and uh and you you can't really dissent
so you know
the kind of
research and peer-review research you
know the amount of research or what is
is done or has been done is
it's become very difficult to uh
to produce uh and and uh and readable in
english
it's it's really less than it should be
because
as we know china is absolutely huge and
is very old and is super active so i
guess the the racial research gap is is
appalling and there is no one that can
speak to you in china because um
because
well
so we
you know in china if you say something
about the regime about the communist
party you lose your job
it's no
it's not joke it's not
would say the chinese people too
are now losing hong kong
because now kong is not gonna be
two-party system this little island
where a steel internet is not censured
because in china internet is his big big
big big bigger draft of censorship
in china you will go in maine and china
you don't have google you are google
china but you don't have
you don't have a website your podcast
will never be seen by by by common
chinese people is sensor
the the blogs we write never be gonna is
is not
possible there's no access to channel
people to blogs and podcasts from the
western world right
youtube is all censored there is no one
video from youtube that as a chinese you
can watch in china
and before that
one he was
he was not too attacked so
you could if you had a little money
you could have a vpn so vpn is the way
to circumvent the the internet and and
what is sensor in your country
uh
you in fact can
view it because because you you are you
you are a user that like if you were in
another country
so
but this now uh and
yes it's like uh
uh ten years ago a little bit less
uh the vpn they say look if you want to
watch in
what is censored in china if you want
let's say to the chinese people if you
want to circumvent
circumvent
with a vpn if you want to watch it with
a vpn like you were not in chennai like
you were in the u.s so you watch
something by essential by the chinese
party if you are caught doing it it's
prison
yeah so you're just a citizen you want
to watch a video on youtube
from the western world it's like
yes israel is
is a is the model of north korea at that
point you go to prison
just because you watch a video from the
western world is this amount of
censorship and and it's well-guarded
because okay you would say oh you know
youtube
and
yeah and people are becoming so rich i
mean the google is gonna own the place
the the
facebook are gonna own the place
so you understand why chinese
what they did is that they've got a
youtu
the equivalent of youtube but it chinese
one
and
and the money of course come to china
and that you would understand why they
do it but it is not
clearly only a condom
question of money is because
yes it's
and there is no way you can say okay
bomb but
people talk will talk will go
on
you know the chinese will talk on their
own
in their own their own
papers or
video or website and so forth no
they can't if they
even if
they
say anything wrong about the
[Music]
bao bao is a very um
famous uh
teacher at university he only said
something about
fundamental freedom or
and yeah he went to prison they died in
prison and so forth only only with a
paper you know
weave on this paper some kind of
political ideas of some of some kind
have you have you um heard any of or or
heard of
me park she's uh she had escaped from
north korea and she's been an author
kind of doing some podcasts recently and
and she she spoke on the state of north
korea and it was so eye-opening to me
it's kind of similar it's kind of
similar to this um it's really seeing
how
similar china and north korea
kind of are becoming in in in a way um
yeah wow it's very difficult for us to
think like that you know to to we have
so much freedom over here in america
that for us to not for me to not be able
to pick up my phone and watch whatever i
want to watch
we can we can't even wrap our heads
around that yeah yes it's true but yes
yes true but
i'm not i'm
i mean it's true yeah but
i wouldn't word it like this because of
course
compared to to this
it is what you just say in comparison
we've got so much freedom right
but um
me i wouldn't forget the fact of our
uh sensor we are in in capitalist
country
that there is uh
there is no way um
there is no way because for example is
uh when you will see so many of these
scandals
uh for example um
financial scandals why you know that for
example uh
it is known the big company they they
cook the books
there's bbc doing uh doing a series on
that it's aaron and
uh
and uh
[Music]
yeah it's it's so it's so cooked or i
mean you know
it's it's it's even it's so gross
usually is that that is a kind of
amusing is because it's so gross
but uh we we
will we lose um
the grasp of any reality basically the
inequality is so gross or for example
the
the the way it's it's uh
it's badly done the way we we show that
if
we are in some profession we're gonna uh
see how much we pollute for example do
you uh just just out of sheer negligence
you know if you if you were doing things
properly and in a different way and if
born this is like a
national level for example if we stop
using the amount of plastic but we know
it's gonna ruin ruin our health run this
planet and so forth and
no if in fact it's true there's no
censorship we can talk about
this you and me
me
i don't even do it under my
true name
because
i've written and i've written maybe in a
liberate liberal way but
about slavery and
about
religious extremism and
and also
veganism and the persecution of
homosexual in in in african countries
are
put in prison because of their sexuality
and so forth and
no one no many people know about it
and also it's uh
it's the way you write you know
yes i'm not so sad but uh
i don't feel i can do
this on
under my own name because
because of a scottie i will be under and
but i know that
that
this is gonna be linked with my living
with my job with the empire but will
look and
and see if they agree with what with
what have been said
uh also there is censorship in
in capitalist countries capitalist uh my
guess is that china
china is capitalist as well and so it is
not
it is not i mean
it's a communist party it's a one uh
party but uh
you know it's an open market so uh
it's not any longer um
uh doing things
you know communally and
so far
whatever yeah but
[Music]
yes for example
a whistleblower have been treated
this is a very excellent way of
of assessing um how much censorship
varies in the country and if i'd say
even in france because you know it's a
bit of a pompous
patriotic reaction
yes in france they are treated
up for english
also we see we see our our system is
changing because
of uh
what we have been told it was
and how it is changing is is so it's
even more shocking
is for example uh
if you uh
if you if you if you investigate on the
on on a company and if
they choose to say that
you know you don't have a proof
enough proof and offense
but
you know to say that this uh this
company really
i've done something very wrong and so
forth for journalists is becoming very
very very dangerous to investigate
and to
to share any information they found
because if it's not proven by air plus b
if it's only witnesses and so forth the
the what they've got to pay the
newspaper
of a journalist to have a
propagating the information is
is really bad
so basically no one is gonna want it to
investigate to say anything any longer
because if you if you say anything
but i mean
of course it is good that you can't say
anything about anyone just to slander
them yeah this is this is good yeah but
i'm not talking about this i'm talking
about um
uh company but uh completely
unscrutinized
they can do whatever way they want of
course they've got so many so many ways
to hide
what
what should be controlled and
should be assessed and should be stopped
because it creates a misery and it's uh
and it's not done and there's only the
journalists left trying to do their job
and they can't do anymore because yeah
so the level of censorship and we know
it also in a capitalist system
where
we know our newspapers are controlled
more and more by one person only
and
and this person are multi-billionaire
and so
independent in independence in
publication is
is uh is all but gone and in university
is the same university and here are
funded by a
detector ship
yeah a university there's a big big
amount of university receiving an
enormous amount of funding from a
country such as saudi arabia china qatar
and so forth yeah so
what if you receive funding from
dictatorship
we know about capta who is
living and thriving on pure slavery on
pure trafficking they all their their
staff they they don't allow them to to
to do anything but
work if they if they go outside they are
caught by the police and
and their passport for phone out of
window and this is yeah and and and
and with this system uh
uh
are totally linked with with with
western one
university nonetheless
yeah it's it's it's scary how
interchangeable or like intertwined
everything really is set where do you
see um where do you see the role
as a journalist yourself
where do you see the role of journalists
right now you know in this time of of um
you know fake news in all of these
um conflicts of interest
there's a lot of journalists who are not
doing their job uh well so what if you
had like if you had to say something to
the other journalists you know what what
would it be i mean because i think we
need we need some
courageous
people right now we need some courageous
journalists who are
doing the hard work and speaking the
truth you know and
not censoring themselves yeah but
i'm not sure about that because there is
a
legal framework
and if
anything that you do is gonna you're
gonna be sure it's gonna be the
enslavement of yourself
uh if you if you know that uh for
example you will
such as
whistleblowers yeah because in that case
journalists are whistleblowers and such
as whistleblowers i mean you know it's
typical uh um
the way it it's a good example of
the framework we will work for example
you you witness something so you know
there is a big problem as an employee
yeah
but
of course you are not the
ceo so there's papers to prove that is
happening
uh
you that you cannot produce this only
the only the the senior that can
pronounce this paper yeah but
nonetheless you go to court and you say
there's this and this and this
only what the judge had to do is to say
okay
so you are a ceo or you are a manager of
this place i need you to give me this
amount of paper to prove
that you are doing things well okay it's
all but what should be happening yeah
but the judge is never ever will will
never ask for this paper never
yeah so they are let so it's impossible
for you to report anyone
because because the the legal framework
is not there here
and so
only what
what is left to you is to do your own
justice which you cannot and on top of
it you just lost your your job doing
this
in case of whistleblower and
certainly the legal framework here will
work perfectly to say that
you have been bad you have been blah
blah blah so you've lost your job but
not only this you you you you lost your
uh
you see
is civic credibility
and also when you've got to find another
job in another company who will do the
same because if they can get away with
it and and earning more money by this
and so being more competitive or more
widespread vegan
is these
criminals are
going to rule at the end because they
just make money out of the misery they
are creating and therefore rule so it's
a vicious
circle and as well i would be very very
you know asking my if for example is is
just what i've heard on
on the radio
today
is to say to
you know to be positive and to say oh
maybe african people you know it's so
cool i just
the courageous people and resilient
people and
and uh
and
there is um
there is many people in the west that
have heard many not many but there's a
few saying that they will react against
talim taliban being back
but this is crazy because if if an
army such as the u.s army
cannot cannot fight the taliban if the
taliban is protected by pakistan yeah
like he has been for years and years
by is pushing for this but there is what
what we know about the isis and
and al qaeda even i think it's isis that
don't like battalion doesn't matter and
yeah it's it's is the same hell they
they have to to they they are here to
offer yeah and on top of it that this
that the taliban is backed by china
and pakistan because pakistan and china
are friends and so forth and the was the
only thing that you say that we can say
because this is the situation wherein is
no no we have to
you know
if we have young people is resilient and
they will have a courage to resist
there's no courage to resist because
they are done
basically they are done by the
uh i in fact is beyond me because um
because of this situation is so
bewildering that
um but uh yeah is there there is no co
courage in in in in their uh
i mean yes very discouraged but uh
uh they're gonna be executed yes
they are they are being executed right
now yeah yeah yeah of course uh yeah i
mean obviously there's there's certain
uh
liberties that we have by being able to
even be courageous so even someone being
able to start a podcast is something
that not everybody has the
the um you know the the chance to do so
do you think do you think that a lot of
these important conversations are going
to start
happening on places like podcasts and um
like the clubhouse app if you've heard
of that
just because clearly we need to get away
from our institutions to have these
important conversations because our
institutions have their own versions of
corruptions and blind spots
so the future of these types of
conversations where we talk about
important things do you think
i mean do you think stuff like this is
kind of how it's going to go
can this make it better like if we look
at the next you know 20 years 10 years
whatever it is
[Music]
how do we get away from the institutions
controlling what's being said and not
said
uh i'm not sure um
[Music]
as i would say but i'm not
full because
it's
so again it's it's not really relevant
to your point but uh like i asked human
trafficking you know there's and and
mirroring censorship i would say yeah
is um
i would give a semen size but we are
i don't think that it looks like if it's
going to get better
for the simple fact that yes there is
awareness and an opening and information
circulating
maybe more awareness i'm not sure
because for example uh
they are very unclose community to to
answer to answer a question here
before of my own experiences are you
circulating the information yeah so the
only uh
um
thing that i have i've got an experience
in a little bit is for facebook you know
a lot of social media uh
information is circulating on facebook
well facebook is a great example right
um
the the circulate the circular
relation of information is just just
only done
within
circles
and very similar circles basically on
facebook if you want information of
human trafficking
first you need to be a member of one of
a group of human trafficking basically
is this yeah
but maybe on group on human rights it
means that you are already one that some
that knows that this problem exists
and then you sign up and then you know
you you become
like a pseudo specialist amateur
but but uh
if if you want if if you are on facebook
i am on facebook i know i've got a very
important information for you
for me to give to you i've got to pay
i cannot come in into your profile and
say you know what jacob did you know
about that right i cannot if i want to
do that or we are from the same group
already we are signed up on on human
trafficking because if if i do something
on human trafficking and we are we are
exchanging
uh while we wear a group of cat lovers
is not gonna happen here i'm gonna be
all censored or removed all my comment
is gonna be removed
or or i'm gonna be removed from the
group you know what i mean yeah so
basically we are trying to um
to build some kind of awareness and and
so forth and it's why but it's not
possible because it's very on close
group and we've got a problem facing
with capitalism is is
the advertisement is king
that is to say anything you want to do
whatever it is for your business or what
you or it is for your organization or
your newspaper
is it
you've got to to pay to contact your
service not free
not free
and
um
so
yeah and you've got this and force and
and also for human trafficking
when the question is you know
is it gonna
get better yeah
uh
the the con the context is a context
where
this word is is is is facing so many
problems
already and that there is so many
problems that we know are too
to come due to our negligence
due to to a menace to be honest
because the amount of problem we're
gonna have with nature for example but
can't survive what we are doing to the
planet it cannot yeah so there's climate
change reversing there as well the level
of pollution and
a poison
that it's every everywhere on air on on
soil on water and so forth
and one day
the plants will stop to grow away and
there's diseases of course diseases on
on the before we had like i don't know
1000 variety of
of cereals and
and
legumes and so forth and now we've got
or 20.
yeah we're not living a very sustainable
future right now at all no
wow um
well i mean we are getting up here in
time so i do want to round the corner
i i i thank you for for not only your
time again but um for just all the work
the work that you do uh it really is
important uh it's powerful and um i mean
i i appreciate everything that you do
set
it's it's it's wonderful and it's uh
it's the right thing to do so thank you
thank you very much for having inviting
me is very nice
yeah yeah of course um so i will include
in the the texted written out
description down below um this will
probably be a few weeks out i'm getting
a little bit of a backlog but i will uh
include your your website and whatnot is
there anything else you'd like to
include is anything anywhere else you
want to send people any listeners yes
well um we talked about the rest so the
rest of what i
i
had to talk in priority is veganism and
the torture we inflict on animals
instead of
feeding ourselves with
with plants that
very healthy and so forth it's not
because i like killing plants but
is to avoid killing animals as
it's a bit complicated philosophically
but yes to stop torturing uh
cars and you know mammals and any
animals here to just to feed ourselves
is
is i think very important because people
people funnily and
we are in culture by so so tightly um
linked with meeting as a
inspirational and
and linked with strength and
wealth and so forth but
there is many people that love
animals and
that
but don't get they are eating them at
the same time so it's why i think it's
very important to
spread the word on veganism
and also
i would like to spread the word about
lgbt people are put into prison for
their sexual orientation in
in in africa in middle east and uh in
any country in i'd say like which
country but
even
a country benefiting from
tourism such as kenya for example
wow well i mean thank you seth i really
really appreciate it thank you for
spreading the word on all of these
things i'll clue that in the description
um it looks like you've been being
featured on some other podcasts as well
so if they search your name um even just
on youtube you can find some more
interviews with set if you enjoyed um or
or you you found it interesting what we
talked about today so
said v uh thanks one more time i hope
you have a good rest of your day
listeners take care of yourselves love
yourself
drink some water stretch just try to be
centered and look out for one another
all right take care bye set
at what age do we learn how to have
better conversations
at what age do we learn to have better
conversations with ourselves
[Music]
no
knowledge is power
[Music]
you